Edson Arturo Rodríguez Govea

Colima, México (CST) - <u>erodstardev@gmail.com</u> <u>Linkedin profile</u> · <u>GitHub</u> · <u>Portfolio</u>

I am a web front-end developer mostly experienced with handling technologies like Vue.js and React.js who loves to learn something new and create simple and complex web pages for process and/or problem improvement.

EXPERIENCE

NOV. 2022 – CURRENT FULLSTACK DEVELOPER, SONATAFY

Management and update of the customer administrative tools, based on automated tests and agile communications between systems.

- Improvement on the client administrative website both on usability and troubleshooting implementing automated tests.
- Contribution to a better planning for the data management architecture from the backend.
- Development of a custom component library from scratch for the client using Vue2 (Options API), taking as reference the most popular ones on the market such as Buefy or Vuetify, focusing on the needs and preferences of the client.
- Creation of endpoints through Node.js consuming information from both GraphQ and a MySQL database.
- Creation of Lambda functions using Node.js to be able to be consumed through the Hasura platform, in what is known as HASURA actions.

Technologies implemented: Vue.js, Jest, Cypress, Node.js, AWS, GraphQL, PostgresSQL, Git, Github.

MAY. 2021 - NOV. 2022

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, HMH SISTEMAS

Software company specialized in web development using React.js and Vue.js

- Planned, designed, and developed 2+ software projects from zero to deploy using agile methodologies.
- Participated in the management of a medicine delivery application where I worked with the Google Maps Platform API creating Polylines, user interfaces and real-time tracking of the shipment. This implementing the GMaps API as well as Vue.js and Sass
- Re-make UX-UI in point of sale application, this new experience was developed using Vue.js and SASS using the BEM methodology
- Implemented reusable components in order to reduce the project development time

Technologies implemented: HTML5, CSS, Sass, React.js, Vue.js (Options and Composition API), Buefy, Bootstrap, Gitlab, Git, i18n.

NOV. 2021 - NOV. 2022

MOBILE TEAM LEAD DEVELOPER, FREEWAY COMPANY (PART TIME)

FreeWay is a startup company focused on the development of mobile applications for freight using the software development methodology Scrum.

- Participated in the creation of the first project coding the main structure of it.
- Develompent of a mobile application using the Flutter framework and consuming
 information through GraphQL queries, where a CRUD was created for the cargo services
 flow in a freight transport application. In addition to this, by being a team lead, I actively
 participate in giving feedback to other developers by doing code reviews, pair coding or
 simply chatting to find the best possible solution.
- Helped to introduce new developers to the environment of the projects, creating solutions and managing a good internal code structure.
- I served as team lead of a mobile development team, actively using the Scrum methodology preparing Sprint planning, Sprint retrospectives as well as creating tickets for new features or issues

Technologies implemented: Flutter, Graphql, Zeplin, GitHub, Git.

EDUCATION

2019 – 2023 – SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, SCHOOL OF TELEMATICS, UNIVERSITY OF COLIMA

ABILITIES

- Intermediate level developer.
- Front-end frameworks management.
- Feedback and support to arrive at the best possible solutions.
- Commitment to teamwork.
- Willingness to learn.
- Team player

TECHNICALL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JS (ES6), Git (Github, Gitlab), Typescript, Vue.js (Vue 2, Vue3), React.js (Context API, Redux), Sass, Bulma, Scrum, Flutter, Figma, Bootstrap, AWS (IAM, Lambda, S3, CloudWatch, Simple Queue Service), NodeJS, GraphQL, Cypress, PostgreSQL